this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at SC - radio dotnet SC radio is
brought to you by the I Triple E
Computer Society I Triple E software
magazine online at computer org slash
software digitalocean is the easiest
cloud platform to deploy manage and
scale applications of any size removing
infrastructure friction and providing
predictability so developers and their
teams can deploy faster and focus on
building software that customers love
with thousands of in-depth tutorials and
an active community we provide the
support you need digitalocean stands out
of the crowd due to its simplicity and
high performance with no billing
surprises try digitalocean for free by
getting a 100 dollar infrastructure
credit at doco / SC radio hi this is
Jeremy Jung for software engineering
radio today I'm speaking with Daniel
Corbett Daniel is the director of
product at H a proxy technologies daniel
has a background in high traffic hosting
environments in both a senior DevOps
position as well as fulfilling the role
of a senior security analyst Daniel has
worked with H a proxy technologies for a
little over a year I'll be speaking with
Daniel about what load balancers do the
different types of load balancers that
exist how H a proxy can be used and how
the roles of load balances are changing
Daniel welcome to software engineering
radio thanks for having me Jeremy I
appreciate it so the first thing I'd
like to discuss is what load is could
you give us a definition sure absolutely
load is basically work that needs to be
done this could be anything from the
need to retrieve information or process
information or file it away somehow
but it's frequently a combination of the
above when it comes to load some of the
limiting factors could be based around
CPU disk or network and these are all
things that servers face when they need
to process load if the load is clients
asking to add two numbers for example
the CPU will be the primary cause of the
load if it's reading or writing
information stored on the server it will
be the disks and in environments with a
variety of types of load each request
can stress one component more
than another requiring careful
distribution of the requests if that's
load then what is a load balancer and
what is it do in relation to that so a
low bouncer is used to distribute
traffic or load to various back-end
services and application servers it
takes the request and it forwards it to
the backend servers which usually reply
directly to the load bouncer this allows
a little bouncer to reply to the client
without the client knowing about the
internal separation or functions of the
back-end network it also prevents
clients from contacting back-end servers
directly which may have security
benefits of hiding the structure of the
internal network itself and is a load
balancer a hardware appliance or is it a
software application what what does it
look like so low bounce rate can be both
although even with hardware appliances
it still relies on some sort of software
to operate in the background
traditionally a lot of load balancing
within enterprise environments relied on
a hardware appliance but it was found
that this model was not scalable or
flexible and was extremely costly with
software base load answers and allows an
organization to run an environment of
their choosing that could be directly
from a cloud provider a virtual machine
or even sourcing their own bare metal
servers the market is trending away from
Hardware appliances and heading towards
software based load balancers due to the
flexibility and the scalability that's
provided one of the things that you
mentioned was that the load balancer is
in front of kind of the origin
application to prevent it from talking
directly to your application servers
what what kind of benefits does that
give you well the low bumps are being in
front of the application server gives
you the security benefit of you're able
to filter particular requests so the
client would be interacting directly
with the load balancer only on port 80
or 443 for example or whatever it is
that your application port is running on
and that limits exposing all of the
other ports on your application to the
to the general internet but it also
allows the backend server application to
be on an internal network only so let's
say you have your low
answer that's listening on external
interface or public IP you can have your
back-end network completely masked from
the internet and not available at all to
to be hid and your load bouncer would
have a route to this internal network
where you can speak to the load bouncers
on the internal network if the load
balancer can be placed in front and the
user never needs a direct connection
does that mean the load balancer axe is
kind of like a proxy and you know
requests correct okay got it
correct that would act as a proxy to the
to the back-end servers and so that
helps to limit just the exposure of your
application server in general when it
comes to to security it's always best to
have you know multiple layers involved
kind of like an onion you know and so
the more layers of security you have the
more protected that you'll be because
even if one particular layer is
penetrated you'll be protected by
another layer and what kinds of
applications should use a load balancer
essentially all types of applications
can benefit from load balancing some
common examples would be web
applications and WebSocket based
applications database systems caching
systems mail servers Redis or memcache
be generally the more moving parts the
back-end has and the more connections it
gets the more important a load bouncer
is to it
if the requests are all coming to the
load balancer how does that not become a
single point of failure it can be the
single point of failure if there's only
one load balancer configured but
typically it's recommended to use some
kind of solution or software which
provides vrrp such as keepalive v4 an
active/passive setup which would this
will give the load balancer a floating
IP address which will move over to the
passive device if the health of the
active load bouncer fails other setups
involve using routing protocols and
route health injection to bring up or
down advertisements based on the health
of the load balancer that would be used
primarily in an active-active setup so I
want to go into a little bit more detail
but
before that why don't we walk through at
a high level what happens when a user
attempts to use an application that's
behind a load balancer what what are the
the steps where someone get would get
routed to the correct server and so on
sure it would start off by a client
resolving a domain name which would
return an IP address that's associated
with a load bouncer and then when the
client connects to that IP address the
load balancer begins processing the
request the first step of this request
processing would be determining which
service is associated with the IP
address and the port being requested as
a load balancer can host many different
services across different IP addresses
or ports at one time and if the
connection is comes in over SSL there
would be a handshake process in which
the client would verify that it is
talking to the right server cipher
suites will be agreed upon and the
certificate and a key exchange will
occur once both ends the client and the
server are happy that they're talking to
the right person so to speak and have
agreed on a key to symmetrically encrypt
the data that they're about to sent then
the request processing can move on and
then once once it moves on the load
balancer then begins to perform any
logic that's set up for that service for
example if the host hostname begin tree
being requested it begins with API the
request may be sent to particular
backends that only handle API requests
you may also perform logic based on a
particular request URI or path to route
to a particular back-end based on that
path this is useful for example when
using a proxy as an API gateway for
example you might have a path forward
slash catalog that you may want to send
to a particular endpoint or back-end and
a separate path forward slash checkout
which you may want to send to another
endpoint or back-end there may also be
various security based logic in effect a
block request coming from a particular
IP address or the rate limit requests
that are going to a particular path an
example this would be if you have a log
in a search or a common functionality on
your site you may want to limit how many
requests a particular client can make
over a period of time to this particular
path then once all of the requests
processing logic is completed the load
balancer would then determine
what load balancing algorithm is being
used round-robin and at least connection
being the most commonly used and then
the load answer would choose a server
based on this algorithm and connect and
connect to it on the client's behalf and
past the full request to the back-end
server optionally though it could use
persistence and route all requests from
a particular user or client to the same
server and then the backend server would
respond directly to the load balancer
which would then check for again there
would be response logic processing that
would happen to check for any logic that
you would want to happen based on the
response for example changing the
response code if necessary sometimes
it's used to hide server errors let's
say that your application server output
an HTTP internal server it should be
code 500 for internal server you could
have your agent proxy server change the
status code to be at 200 which would
have masked the fact that an error
occurred in the background and then
after the response logic processing is
completed it would then send the
response back to the client our load
balancer is suitable for any type of
traffic you had mentioned HTTP HTTPS but
what if you're using raw TCP sockets or
UDP do load balancers also apply in that
case yes they do you know suitable for
essentially all types of traffic each a
proxy supports both HTTP based load
balancing at layer 7 and TCP base load
balancing out layer 4 when it comes to
UDP based applications and is typically
recommended to do load balancing at a
lower layer using something along the
lines of LVS but we are planning to
bring UDP support to AJ proxy there's a
new standard coming out called quick
which is essentially HTTP 2 over UDP and
this is something that H a proxy is also
scheduled to support you mentioned was a
tell us what is that LVS of our Linux
virtual server it's a set of integrated
software components used for load
balancing TCP or UDP at the kernel level
one of the main components is IP vs or
IP virtual server and it primarily
operates on layer 4
I think we're gonna get into Pacific
layers in a little bit would you put a
load balancer in front of a database or
a case or is it more specific to your
custom application code absolutely for a
database you could have the load
balancer listening on a specific IP
address that routes traffic only to
servers that are set for reading only
and another IP address that could be
used for routing to a single master
server with a secondary master that is
set to be a backup and it would only be
used if the primary master fails for a
cache scenario the logon star could be
used with a consistent hash based load
balancing which ensures that the same
URI will always be directed to the same
cache server which would have the
content as act they were hot within each
cache next I'd like to talk about the
different types of load balancers load
balancers are sometimes discussed within
the context of the open systems
interconnection network layers could you
explain briefly what those layers are
and how they relate to load balancing
sure so the major ones for load
balancing would be layer seven layer
five and layer four layer seven load
balancers understand the application can
do things like direct the request based
on the host header inject headers into
it into the request etc later foreign
layer 5 allows routing without
completely understanding the protocol
but it can still perform Limited
inspection for persistence and routing
based on patterns found within that data
to give an example of this is if a
client comes in and you're doing layer
for load balancing you'd be able to only
apply routing decisions based on what
the client IP may be or what the
destination IP may be and or even you
know let's say you have a scenario where
you have access control list setup ACLs
and you don't want to allow a particular
IP to connect to your back-end maybe you
have a sensitive back-end that you only
want to allow people on VPN to connect
to so you could say you could create
some logic that only allows traffic from
a particular IP address
blocks particular IP addresses format
accessing your application server but
then with layer seven you'd be able to
go even further than that let's say that
you didn't want a particular user agent
to be able to access your application
server you know maybe that to W get or
curl you know just as a quick example
you may say I don't want this particular
user agent to be able to access my
back-end application so you would use
layer layer seven load balancing to
inspect the full request headers and
filter those requests that matched that
user agent and does H a proxy served
both of these scenarios yes H a proxy
does within H a proxy there's two
configuration modes that could be used
one is TCP and that would be for layer
four and the other one is HTTP which
would be for layer seven based
processing would you ever use the two
together and and if so would it be in
kind of a tiered setup or would they
live on the same machine what would that
look like architecture was yeah you can
use them together typically a layer four
base load balancer would sit in front of
a layer seven base load balancer if you
were gonna go that route but it's not
necessary you can have them separate
from each other but you can also combine
them sometimes having a layer four base
load balancer in front of your later
seven load balancer can help when when
you have extremely long live connections
and you want to load balanced the layer
seven load balancers themselves which
may have established connections you'd
be able to do that easier with a layer
four in front of it and if someone was
looking into adding load balancing to
their application or their downsides to
adding additional layers should they
start at layer seven and go to layer
four after kind of what should be the
process that someone goes through when
they're thinking about adding loot
balancing well it depends on what their
their needs are for example if if your
needs are extremely simple and you don't
have
any logic that you need to happen based
on any routing object that to happen
based on request paths or request
headers or or things of that nature you
can go with layer four but you know
layer seven is also beneficial even if
you don't have even if you don't have
any requirements of routing based on
data found within the request there are
some security features that come with it
allowing you to filter particular
content or you know activate a web
application firewall for example things
like that I'd say that from my
perspective layer seven is always great
to use but if you're just getting
started in load balancing layer four can
be appropriate to if you don't have any
specific needs again like if you're not
trying if you don't need an API gateway
or you don't need to do any request
processing or response processing or
inspection layer 4 it can be suitable
you know it's a tough one to answer
because I think everyone that every
every users needs would be different
basically so I think that you couldn't
go wrong with using either of the two
but with layer seven load balancing you
you get a lot more flexibility in power
when it comes to handling requests if
you don't have any particular
requirement for the things in layer
seven it may still make sense to start
with that just because it gives you the
flexibility to use those if you find
that you do need them later right
exactly and you know just to just to go
a little bit further into it is that a
checkbox you fully supports the HTTP
protocol so you would gain the benefit
of the protocol understanding
capabilities which you know as we
mentioned above it allows you to route
based on the information found in the
request but it also allows you to add or
remove headers or rewrite the request
itself so it there's a lot of just
benefit within layer seven in general so
it's typically and especially in the
current climate of application servers
it's it's typically a lot more
beneficial to use let's start with layer
seven next I'd like to get more into the
specifics of each a proxy first what is
H a proxy
so hey foxy is the world's fastest and
most widely used software load bouncer
it provides an extremely fast reliable
and flexible solution offering high
availability load balancing and reverse
proxying for TCP and HTTP based
applications it is particularly suited
for very high traffic applications and
powers quite a number of the world's
most visited ones over the years has
become the de facto standard open source
load balancer and is shipped with most
mainstream Linux distributions and is
often deployed by default in cloud and
micro service platforms why was H a
proxy originally created and what kinds
of gaps wasn't filling so H a proxy was
originally created and known as C procs
which was just a compressing TCP proxy
which supported gzip based compression
it was created by Willy Toro in 1998 and
then in 2001 he added persistence to
offload a failing load balancer that he
was working with and aged a proxy 1.0
was officially released prior to H a
proxy it was common for organizations to
just use pure hardware based load
balancer mmm so would that have been
devices like the f5 hardware load
balancers correct correct
yeah and like you were discussing
earlier it sounds like that's becoming
less and less common now I guess due to
the flexibility of software load
balancers is that correct yes they it's
it's the flexibility and scalability
that that they provide in general
because you know typically when you were
buying a hardware based load balancer
before you would have to plan how much
capacity you may need you know you'll
have to estimate what your traffic needs
are not only now but maybe a couple
years into the future because a hardware
based load bouncer could be quite
expensive and costly and
we've talked to many customer customers
of ours who over time they weren't able
to make the appropriate decision they
thought that their traffic level was
going to be one way but then they ended
up having a lot more traffic or a lot
less traffic and each of these can
impact the organization in a particular
way so if you don't plan accordingly and
you have a lot more traffic than what
you are originally provisioned for well
now you need to purchase another very
expensive piece of hardware to extend on
but also there's some traffic patterns
that you know maybe in some cases you're
you have burst type traffic you know
let's just think of a situation where
maybe you you're running an application
that the peak traffic bursts on the
weekend but during the week you don't
have much traffic or think of situations
such as Black Friday you know we all
know to be an extremely popular shopping
time in the United States and you know
do you need to buy an additional
hardware load balancer to accommodate
for that peak traffic or what the
software load answer provides the
flexibility and the scalability to scale
up or down as needed based on your
traffic demand and that's primarily
because you're using commodity hardware
as opposed to specialized machines yes
you could be you could source your own
commodity hardware but you can also
deploy in a virtual machine environment
for example maybe you have a couple
beefy servers that are already
configured to host virtual machines you
can deploy your load bouncers there and
scale them up or down or also similarly
within cloud-based markets so you know
you can deploy within AWS or Google
Cloud or Microsoft Azure and so that
allows you the flexibility to to scale
up or down based on your applications
needs we discussed a little bit about
how H a proxy supports layer 7 and layer
4 load balancing what are the cases
where there would be load balancers
upstream of H a proxy
I think you had mentioned that DNS for
example could possibly serve as a load
balancer but would be serving that role
upstream the two most common ways to
handle this would be either using global
server load balancers also known as GS
LP which is based on typically on DNS
and also BGP anycast so the first one
with GSLV solutions an example of this
would be AWS route 53 which uses
intelligent DNS to direct client to
specific locations based on the clients
location for example if the user in
Europe performs a DNS request to your
site a GS lb solution will respond to
the request with an IP address from your
particular European point of presence
there are open source solutions that
provide this such as powered DNS is one
with a geoip back-end if you want to try
rolling your own DNS GSLV setup the
second solution that I mentioned BGP
anycast it relies on the fact that
routing decisions on the Internet are
based on the shortest autonomous system
path or a s path with any cast you
announced the same prefix to the
internet from multiple point of presence
locations so when a client makes the
request they get routed to the point of
presence closest to them to utilize BGP
anycast your infrastructure needs to
have the ability to speak BGP with your
upstream provider so you can advertise
your anycast prefix but also since the
smallest prefix that you're allowed to
advertise on the internet is a slash 24
you will need to at least have a slash
24 that you can dedicate to any cash but
once you you you probably heard me
mention multiple times points of
presence within this when you have
multiple points of presence set up
within each of these locations that's
where you would have your multiple
active active h8 proxy setups running so
as I had mentioned if you have a user in
Europe that performs a dns request and
they get sent to your European point of
presence at that
you would have as many h8 proxy
instances as is required for your
traffic level that could be four if
eight it could be ten but the this would
allow you to essentially load balanced
your load bouncers globally basically
whenever you have more than one H a
proxy instance and you want the client
to be able to like you said be load
balanced to each of those you would use
either the BGP any casts or the GS lb
and that that's how the client would get
redirected to one of your H a proxy load
balancers correct we see we typically
see this setup and in extremely high
traffic environment such as tech
companies are a big one we have a few ad
tech customers who serve billions of
requests per day and they have global
network and global platforms and and
things of that nature so the this is the
common setup for some of the world's
largest sites if you're a smaller
organization does that mean that you
would only have a single H a proxy load
balancer I'm trying to picture what that
looks like
no it's typically never recommended to
just have a single load balancer active
what we find some of our smaller
customers use is say an active passive
setup and with an active passive setup
you would use software such as keepalive
d that would help to failover an IP
address from one server to another so
you would have your active load balancer
and then your passive load balancer the
active load balancer would have the IP
address at all times but using a
software such as keepalive D you would
be able to detect what the health is of
the active server and if the active
server fails in some particular way the
IP address would automatically move over
to the passive device or server
I see so you would be running more than
one but it would actually be one
fielding all the requests until the
second passive server detected a problem
with the act
correct and that that's what we find
some smaller organizations are using
that that don't have so much traffic at
the moment it's the easiest to set up
and get going and it doesn't require you
to have a network engineering team to
make the magic happen
you had mentioned keep alive D could you
explain kind of at a high level what
that is so keep alive D is essentially a
routing software that it allows you to
have an active in passive it set up for
an IP address so what you would do is
you can have it monitor any variety of
circumstances so you can have it do
health checking on its local instance to
know if the application is still running
let's say if H a proxy is still running
or something of that nature and then
simultaneously the secondary server is
doing pinks at a low level protocol to
establish itself whether the active
server just spontaneously crashes for
example and keep alive D would be
running on both the active and the
passive server and each server would
have a priority set to it so your active
server would have a higher priority than
your passive server and if something
fails on the active server the passive
server would automatically take over
this IP address with keep alive feet
keep alive II would essentially move the
IP address to the passive server next
I'd like to go into how a load balancer
selects which server to pass the clients
requests onto earlier you had mentioned
round-robin could you define how
round-robin works and what some other
options might be sure absolutely so with
round-robin each server is used in turns
according to their weights this is the
smoothest and the fairest algorithm when
the server's processing time remains
equally distributed some of the other
algorithms that I can talk about are
lease connections and with lease
connections to server with the lowest
number of connections receives the
connection this algorithm is typically
used where very long sessions are
expected such as L
that sequel database servers or
Microsoft Terminal Services but with
that said I'd like to go into a few
other of the load balancing algorithms
in general because agent proxy supports
a wide variety of other load balancing
algorithms such as random which selects
a server at random while respecting the
server's weights there's also source
load balancing where the source IP
address is hashed and divided by the
total weight of the running servers to
designate which server will receive that
request and what that does is it ensures
that the same client IP address will
always reach the same server as long as
no other server goes up or down but the
options are endless when it comes to
load balancing algorithms within each a
proxy as it can also load balance off of
a specific request header or a URL
parameter or anything for that matter
you mentioned a wait for the server how
is the weight determined the weight is
something that will be determined within
the configuration so it is typically
used if you have different servers with
let's just say different hardware
specifications let let's assume that you
had a setup where you had some old
servers that a back-end application
server set up but you started purchasing
new Hardware beefier and better you know
you don't want to equally distribute the
load to your new beefier servers at the
same level that you're distributing the
load to your older legacy servers let's
say so with that you would use weight to
send more of the requests to the newer
hardware and a fraction of the request
to the legacy hardware
digitalocean is the easiest cloud
platform to deploy manage and scale
applications of any size removing
infrastructure friction and providing
predictability so developers and their
teams can deploy faster and focus on
building software that customers love
with thousands of in-depth tutorials and
an active community we provide the
support you need digitalocean stands out
of the crowd due to its simplicity and
high performance with no billing
surprises try digitalocean for free by
getting a 100 dollar infrastructure
credit at doco /se radio and how can h a
proxy tell if a server is in a faulted
state if it's either not processing
requests at all or is processing them
very slowly yeah that's a great question
and this is actually where load
balancers shine in general and H a proxy
itself does actually so there are
several options when it comes to dealing
with health checks within a proxy you
could do an active health checking such
as a simple TCP port check a service
specific health check for things like my
sequel or reddish or even send a full
HTTP request and search for a pattern
within the response or a response status
code so for example with dissent when
you send the full HTTP request and
you're looking for a particular response
maybe you have a Status page up let's
just call it status dot HTML and let's
say that typically this data studies GML
page would contain the string okay
agent proxy would connect fetch status
dot HTML and then it would look for the
string okay but if it found any other
strings such as fail or it didn't find
any content within the file at all or it
didn't receive a response it would
consider that server as unhealthy but to
to go further a little bit into that ATM
proxy also allows you to set it send a
particular string and match against mesh
the response against the pattern on
other protocols that are not HTTP so
this allows for testing just about any
protocol whether its ASCII based or
binary and it also allows you for
testing multiple
and another active health check that's
extremely powerful is called an agent
check and in this case an administrator
would configure an agent that would run
on a back-end server and it's checking a
variety aspects on the backend server
it's possibly monitoring the load memory
usage or other local server metrics and
then the agent has the ability to adjust
the weight of the server for example if
the load starts creeping up the agent
can lower the weight so the server gets
lat less traffic or optionally it can
remove a server altogether from a
receiving requests until the server has
recovered and finally a to a proxy also
offers passive health checking and
passive health checking essentially
allows a tape proxy to monitor what kind
of responses that application is sending
to the client and if it starts seeing an
application generating too many errors
to a client once it hits a defined
threshold they can automatically disable
that server from the cluster for a
period of time this would be activated
within a proxy using what's called the
observe keyword so you can you can have
this activated simultaneously with
active health checks so you could be
performing your active health checks but
the passive health checks too to catch
situations that maybe the active health
check is not generating where an
application begins generating an
anonymous amount of errors to a client
and these configurations you're talking
about in terms of checking for specific
headers or specific content is this
configuration and H a proxy or is there
some ability to actually program logic
and H a proxy like how does that look to
the some of the person who's setting
this up yeah most of it would be just a
configuration line within H a proxy it
really depends on what you want to do
for for an agent check for example it'll
require in a configuration line with
Nha proxy but it would also require that
you have an agent running somewhere
that's answering the record agent proxy
would connect to the agent and the agent
would need to respond accordingly with
the proper data but yet typically these
would all be configuration options that
you would apply but they're very easy
and simple to use or get started next
I'd like to talk about a few other
scenarios we talked a little bit about
whether a client will connect to the
same server on subsequent requests is
that just something that you would
configure at the load balancer level how
would you determine whether or not the
client gets the same server or not it
depends if you want to have persistence
it's not always required so if you do
intend to to serve persistence or you do
require persistence there are several
ways that it can handle it so one could
be persistence can be maintained using
the source IP address of the client a
cookie or it can also use any kind of
data fetched from the request in stored
in something that aged a proxy called
stick tables next I'd like to talk a
little bit about designing an
application with the load balancer in
mind when someone's designing an
application what are recommendations you
have to make sure they can take full
advantage of a load balancer essentially
there are a few things that a developer
can do to ensure that their application
is compatible with a load bouncer and
that typically involves not sorting any
particular client data or or that's
needed to prefer to for the application
to work locally you know you typically
want to store this data with
in a centralized database or object
stores such as memcache key or Redis
things of that nature those are the the
primary tips is just to not store any
data locally so basically minimizing any
kind of state and that will make it so
that the load balancer can call any kind
of server which really gets you the full
benefit correct correct how does the
load balancers stay aware of what
servers are available is this something
that somebody would enter IPS into a
config file or is there some other
method so there's a there's a few
methods that are involved so the the
most common method has always been you
know you add the IP addresses to the
configuration file and then the load
balancer would be aware of the new
server but there's newer features that I
have to have evolved one of them
involves using what we call the runtime
api with nh8 proxy and the runtime api
operates off of either a UNIX socket or
a tcp based socket and within the
configuration you would essentially
establish what we call a server template
and the server template would
essentially say how many servers you
would and expect to scale to or and and
and you can leave padding in there so
let's say yeah you know you think
maximum you'll scale to 20 well you can
set this to 30 or 40 or whatever it may
be and then you would use the runtime
API to actually establish a server so
the server template I mentioned would
kind of be like a placeholder and then
you would use the runtime api to
actually set a real server IP address or
end port combination to debate that
particular server within the load
bouncer and this can be automated as I
said it it's a UNIX socket or TCP based
socket in it it just accepts and sends
ASCII information ask you data but then
there's also another method that HTM
proxy supports and that's called DNS
service discovery and DNS service
discovery allows AJ
proxy to be configured to look at just a
host name and that host name would
either would be either in a survey
record or an a record and both of these
would contain multiple records within
them of all the servers that the
application should serve to and then
this integrates great with products such
as hoshi corpse console for example but
when using this you know we typically
find that SRV records are are the most
powerful feature to integrate with
because the SRV records allows you to
define multiple things within it not
only the IP address but the port that
the application is listening on as well
as the weight that you want that
application to have within the load
bouncer so it sounds like just to
summarize from the simplest there's a
configuration file next there's a
runtime api where the developer could
actually have an application that was
communicating via sockets to h a proxy
to tell it what IP czar up and then
finally there's kind of pushing it all
to dns where h a proxy will check the
SRV records at the dns level to know
what's available and what's not yeah
absolutely
next I'd like to talk about H a proxy in
the context of the load balancing
ecosystem I think a lot of people are
familiar with nginx and how it's a web
server but that it also serves as a load
balancer how does H a proxies role
differ from the role of nginx H a proxy
was built from the ground up to be a
load answer we're very proud to do one
thing and be excellent at doing that one
thing the primary difference of H a
proxy over nginx in the terms of load
balancing is that it is faster and more
efficient while using less resources to
do so and this information is easily
found online from a presentation that
booking.com did when they were
interested in switch
off of there f5 device and they were
comparing AJ proxy versus nginx and they
performed non-biased benchmarks to
figure out which application load
balancer was the best for them and they
published these online and they did a
presentation at a conference at some
point on this and within their
presentation it shows that AJ proxy was
not only faster use less CPU usage but
also allow for more connections in
general one other major difference we
find when we compare H a proxy to nginx
is that nginx does not have a
full-featured logical operator support
their mantra is if is evil and you'd be
hard-pressed to use the end operator
when performing complex logical decision
any system administrator a system
engineer DevOps person who has
experience with the nginx configuration
file is probably fully aware of the
limitations that has when it comes to
using if statements again whereas H a
proxy fully supports if and/or as well
as not operators allowing the user to
have full control over the decisions
that are made and we actually encourage
the use of these logical operators as
this is how you could take advantage of
some of the most complex or take
advantage of some of the very complex
and advanced routing or logic decisions
that could be made by H a proxy next I'd
like to kind of compare H a proxy to the
fact that a lot of cloud providers are
now providing manage load balancing
services you have Google cloud load
balancing there's Amazon elastic load
balancing and Azure and so there's all
sorts of cloud services that are
providing load balancing how do these
managed services differ from H a proxy
so we find that these services only
allow a small control over the decisions
users would like to make when load
balancing typically they're in the form
of just a few check boxes within H a
proxy the decisions are endless
we give you the building blocks to build
what you like we do find though that
these services can complement each a
proxy by sitting in front of that in
front of it as a network load balancing
layers such as Amazon's NLB their
network load bouncer and so ok so it
sounds like you might want to use them
in conjunction I believe you had also
mentioned before that Amazon provides
DNS base load balancing with route 53 so
in that case they would be serving the
role of would it be a layer 3 load
balancer in front of the H a proxy load
balancer yes so using using it in that
scenario it would just help to bring you
you know an active active set up of H a
proxy its instances recently there was a
new load balancer or service proxy built
called envoy are you familiar with the
project and and how do you feel that it
differs from H a proxy
yeah we are familiar about it on envoy
ways a new player to the game as you say
um and it's gonna definitely be
interesting to watch it as a product to
mature and grow but we found that in
many areas they seem to be working
backwards on the technology where we're
working forwards and what I mean by that
is it appears that they've added a lot
of the newer hyped technology first to
gain attention and now they're working
backwards and adding some of the basic
load dancing features that many have
come to a joy and find necessary when it
comes to load balancing at the moment
the product is still very young so it's
hard to judge where they will be in the
future
finally I want to talk about how load
balancing has kind of progressed and in
its future when load balancing first
started application architecture was
typically monoliths and then as we kind
of progress there's been more of
service-oriented architecture or
micro-services type of design how has
that changed the the role of load
balancing
so yeah you're absolutely right
load-balancing has changed tremendously
over the last decade we've seen the
switch from layer four load balancers to
application delivery controllers or ABCs
which are later seven reverse proxies
but it's still on a hardware platform
and then we've seen the move over to
software both base load balancers
traditionally organizations would
purchase a hardware load balancer and
would need to estimate their levels of
traffic as I had mentioned earlier well
into the future
when making these purchases from there
and move to running software base load
balancers or bare metal servers and
virtual machines both hardware based or
software on bare metal and also software
on virtual machines again but at this
point in time they would still be
serving a monolithic application and
from their load balancers moved into the
cloud or continued to run on bare metal
servers in virtual machines but with the
back-end application being a micro
service for micro services this brought
a whole new set of requirements in terms
of service discovery as we had had
discussed one popular way to handle it
as I mentioned is through DNS using a
server you're a records and then micro
services brought containers and
container orchestration platforms such
as kubernetes and then containers showed
a rise in the sidecar proxy which would
run alongside your application container
and speak to the application directly
while you would have your edge proxy
speaking directly to the sidecar proxy
you mentioned containers and container
orchestration kubernetes provides a form
of load balancing but then you also
mentioned how each a proxy could be used
as a sidecar how does the use of H a
proxy relate to the load balancing that
exists in kubernetes so kubernetes
allows you to plug in different software
load balancers and each a proxy supports
kubernetes with its community made and
commercially supported ingress
controller
to close us out could you summarize the
benefits that developers get by
employing load balancing
absolutely so having a little bouncer
within your infrastructure can increase
the scalability and specifically the
scalability of your back-end application
servers and we will provide redundancy
and reduce downtime with increased
performance and give you the the ability
to efficiently manage failures it also
provides increased flexibility with when
it comes to advanced logic or routing
decisions that you may need to apply and
finally it provides a centralized
application security at the edge of your
network finally how can people follow
you online you could follow me on
twitter at daniel Corbett underscore my
last name is spelled cor B as in boy he
is an Edward T as in Tom T as in Tom so
again that's at Daniel Corbett
underscore on Twitter or you can also
find me on our community slack chat
which is found at slack H a proxy org or
if you prefer to use IRC IRC on the free
known native Network hashtag H a proxy
Daniel thank you so much for coming on
the show we had a great conversation and
I look forward to seeing what comes next
for H a proxy thank you so much for
having me I really appreciate it it's
been great
this has been Jeremy Jung for software
engineering radio thank you for
listening digitalocean is the easiest
cloud platform to deploy manage and
scale applications of any size
removing infrastructure friction and
providing predictability so developers
and their teams can deploy faster and
focus on building software that
customers love with thousands of
in-depth tutorials and an active
community we provide the support you
need digitalocean stands out of the
crowd due to its simplicity and high
performance with no billing surprises
try digitalocean for free by getting a
100 dollar infrastructure credit at doco
/sc radio thanks for listening to se
Radio an educational program brought to
you by Archer police software magazine
for more about the podcast including
other episodes visit our website at se -
radio net to provide feedback you can
comment on each episode on the web site
or reach us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter
or through our slack channel at SC
radio.com you can also email us at team
@ SC - radio net this and all other
episodes of se radio is licensed under
Creative Commons license 2.5 thanks for
listening
[Music]